传统的"开学日"薄烤饼
Traditional "First day of school" Pancakes.
-画个奶油笑脸不  -老爸  我都上高中了
- Whipped-cream smile? - Dad, I'm in high school now.
直接挤进我嘴里就行
Just put it in my mouth.
好了  太恶心了  快住手
Okay, that's disgusting. Stop it.
快省省这发号施令的架势
Hey, save some of that bossing people around
留着去办公室使  女士
for the office, lady.
休假20年后
After a 20-year vacation,
克莱尔终于要重回职场了
Claire is rejoining the work force.
那可不是休假
Not a vacation.
但我要去我爸的橱柜公司开始新工作了
But I am starting a job at my dad's closet company.
他打算栽培我日后接手公司
He's kind of grooming me to take over.
我有市场营销方面的专业背景
I have a background in marketing.
我非常为她骄傲
I'm so proud of her.
说到市场  我们家的牛奶喝完了
Oh, uh, speaking of marketing -- we're out of milk.
我其实挺紧张的
I'm actually kind of nervous.
你一定会表现得很好的
You're gonna be great.
记住  一旦碰到麻烦
And remember, if you get into a jam,
就来一段我教你的模仿秀
just do the impression I taught you.
嘿  你可以把你的衣服挂在我身体里
Hey. You can hang your clothes in me.
克里斯托弗-步入式衣柜
Christopher walk-in closet.
我死也不会那么做
I'm not doing that.
放松点  老妈  你是给外公干活
Okay, relax, mom. You're working for grandpa.
都算不上真正意义上的工作
It's not even a real job.
就跟夏天时  我给老爸打工一样
It's like that summer when I worked for dad.
他只是试图在帮我树立信心
He was just trying to make me feel good about myself.
不是真的需要我帮忙
He didn't really need my help.
不是这样的
That's not true.
我确实需要你帮我分发宣传单
I needed your help distributing all those fliers.
我确实也分了  看我眼色
And I did. Wink, wink.
你怎么现在就在做作业了
How are you already doing homework?
我都高三了  得考好点才行
It's junior year. I have to get good grades.
你不知道现在外面竞争多激烈吗
Don't you know how competitive it is out there?
别再给我施加压力了
Stop pressuring me!
好端端的小孩变成这副鬼样子
You know, this is what happens to kids
完全是因为缺乏性活动
when they're not sexually active.
你不用去学习吗
Don't you have some studying to do?
拜托  我上的是社区大学
Please, it's community college.
他们只会让你带根固体胶去上学
They tell you to bring a glue stick.
你好
Hello.
没错  就是他  那位  我
Yes, this is he -- him -- me.
第一次就说对了
Right the first time.
我马上过去
I'll be right there.
米奇尔  就是这个
Mitchell, that was it.
等的就是这电话  我要过去了
That was the call. I'm going in.
由于预算削减  我的初中音乐教师岗位
Due to budget cuts, my position as middle-school music teacher
被撤销了
has been eliminated,
所以我一直在当高中替补教师
So I've been working as a high-school sub.
好耶
Ka-ching!
我从没想到还会收到"使命召唤"呢
I never know when I'll be summoned to swoop into action.
我有点像蝙蝠侠
I'm kind of like batman.
但我接到的不是蝙蝠求救图案  而是一通电话
But except for a bat-signal, I get a phone call.
是啊  你还是发现了点差异
Yeah, you found the one difference.
我也不想错过她的开学日
I hate to miss her first day,
但你能送莉莉去学校吗
but do you mind taking Lily to school?
小卡  今天吗
Oh, Cam, today?
我得准备跟查理的会面
I got to prep for my meeting with Charlie.
我跟他只有一小时会谈时间
I only get him for an hour
那还是趁着他在阿斯彭和卡波间的度假间隙
between his vacations in Aspen and Cabo.
你得去当面跟他对质
Okay, you need to confront him
告诉他  他那点无聊的中年危机
and tell him his pathetic little midlife crisis
会让你无法完成你的工作
is making it impossible for you to do your job.
因为他是个谦逊接受批评的人吗
Because he responds so well to criticism.
不  他会炒了我  然后我们就不得不在
No, he'll fire me, and then we'll end up
你家的谷仓里举行婚礼
having to get married in your family's barn.
我们得抓紧时间预定了
Oh, well, we need to book that soon
因为春天是方形舞季
because spring is hoedown season,
接着又是夏季的剧团下乡演出  所以...
And then you get right into summer stock, so...
我才不相信你说的
I don't believe any of that.
好了  如果要由我送莉莉  我得快点
All right, if I'm gonna take Lily, I need to hurry.
莉莉  甜心  快穿上衣服
Lily, sweetheart, let's get you dressed.
我衣服都穿好一小时了
Hey, I've been dressed for an hour.
快点  我可不能迟到  我会掉队的
Come on, I can't be late. I'll fall behind.
我有时总会忘记考虑她的亚洲人特性
Sometimes I forget to factor in the Asian.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：泽生  小饭  冰蓝  3CC醉芝士
时间轴：aaabao    校对：Ethan-泽生  后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第二集
伙计  我知道新学校会有点令人恐惧
Buddy, I know a new school can be scary,
所以给你点小建议
so a little advice --
你每碰到一个新朋友  就赞美对方几句
Every time you meet someone new, pay them a compliment.
比如  我喜欢你的头发
Like, um, "I love your hair."
腿法不错啊  你笑起来真美
"Awesome kicks." "You have a beautiful smile."
好了  老爸  我去跟那边那个大块头说
Okay, dad, I'll tell that big guy over there
他笑起来很美
that he's got a beautiful smile.
很好  皮肤啊  颧骨啊  随你怎么编
Fine. Skin, cheekbones, make it your own.
你能不能别一路跟着我进去
Um, could you maybe not walk me all the way in?
什么
What?
从这里开始我自己走就行
I've got it from here.
当然  好吧  跟你老爸抱
Sure. Yeah. Okay. Give your dad a --
去吧  艾丽克斯
Off you go. Alex!
曼尼  你为什么这么安静
Ay, Manny, why are you so quiet?
因为高中开学第一天而紧张吗
Are you nervous because of your first day in high school?
老妈  在哥伦比亚待了一个夏天
Mom, after spending a summer in Colombia,
我已经脱胎换骨了
I'm a changed man.
天呐  你看到了什么
Oh, my God, what did you see?!
没什么
Nothing,
但我现在是个乘过喷气飞机跨国旅行的阔少了
but I am an international jet-setter now.
我很高端大气上档次
I'm sophisticated.
你觉得姑娘们会因为这个而注意你吗
And you think that the girls are gonna pick up on this?
如果不行  我还有个"无人照顾的儿童"的标志
If not, I still have my "Unaccompanied minor" Sign.
我真不敢相信
Ay, I cannot believe
我的小宝贝都要上高中了
that my little baby's going to the high school.
老妈  快住手  你这是让我出丑呢
Mom, stop. You're embarrassing me.
今天也是我开学第一天  我可以跟你抱抱
It's my first day, too. I could use a hug.
滚出
Go!
-你好啊  歌洛莉亚  -好啊  菲尔
- Hey, Gloria. - Hi, Phil.
高中开学第一天啊
First day of high school, huh?
曼尼兴奋吗
Is Manny excited?
他今天早上5点就起床熨衣服了
Ay, he was up at 5:00 in the morning, ironing.
不过他郁闷的时候也这么做
Ay, but he does that, too, when he's depressed,
我也不知道是什么情况
so now I don't know.
卢克怎么样
How was Luke?
很好啊  他挺舍不得跟我告别的
Great. Yeah, he had a hard time saying goodbye.
但是不管怎样  我要买杯咖啡去
But, um, anyway, I think I'm gonna go get a cup of coffee.
-我能跟你一起去吗  -行啊
- Can I go with you? - Yeah.
老兄  我正在对美女发动攻势呢
Dude, I'm kind of working something here.
要几辆卡车
How many trucks would that take?
等我一会儿  弗雷德
Give me a minute, Fred.
新来的姑娘来了
New girl just walked in.
你这话真恶心  那是我女儿
That's disgusting. She's my daughter.
亲爱的  你看起来美极了
Sweetheart, you look terrific.
真的吗
Are you sure?
因为我还带了领一件衬衫在...在这里
'cause I have another blouse in -- in here.
里面只有这一样东西  衬衫和一副眼镜
It's the only thing in here, that and a pair of glasses
以防我需要读点什么  看起来聪明一点
In case I need to read something or look smarter.
放松
Relax.
今天是你第一天工作
It's your first day.
不会搞砸的  那是什么
Impossible to blow it. What are those?
饼干  我给工作人员做的
Oh, cookies -- I made them for the office.
大错误  弗雷德  再给我点时间
Huge mistake. Fred, two more seconds.
我这里出了点状况  把饼干放下
I got a situation here. Put the cookies down.
-为什么  -你是管理层
- Why? - You're management.
那让你显得费尽心机
Makes you look desperate.
显得你很渴望让大家都喜欢你
Makes you look like you want everyone to like you.
我确实很想让大家都喜欢我
I do want everyone to like me.
你想让大家都尊重你
You want everyone to respect you.
你就得冷酷  树立距离感
You got to be tough. Keep your distance.
也许我们是不同类型的管理人
Well, maybe we are different kinds of managers.
是啊  但你归我管  把饼干留下吧
Yeah, I'm yours. Just leave the cookies.
瞧瞧你  我的一年级宝贝
Look at you, my big first-grader.
好了  我希望你交到很多朋友
All right, I want you to make so many friends
享受欢乐时光
and have so much fun.
我得走了  迫不及待要去学习了
Got to go! I can't wait to learn!
-小心点  -什么
- Be careful! - What?
没什么
Nothing.
请不要迟到  快点  情况不错
Please do not be late. Let's go. Looking good.
布朗校长
Uh, uh, Principal Brown?
-什么事  -你好  我是卡梅隆・塔克
- Yes. - Hi. I'm Cameron Tucker.
我接到了电话  要我今天代课
I was called in to sub today.
对哦  你是来代替哈利老师的  你好
Oh, yeah, you're in for Mrs. Hurley. Hello.
-你好  -她得去康复中心戒瘾
- Hello. - She has come down with a sudden case of rehab.
好好干吧
So do a good job
这可能是个长期职位
'cause this could be a permanent position.
你就当自己是件结实的老牛仔背心吧
Well, prepare to feel like an old denim vest
因为我会亮瞎你的眼
because I'm about to "Be-dazzling" You.
我不知道那是什么意思  但好吧
I don't know what that means, but okay.
我教哪门课
So, what am I teaching?
高阶历史
A.P. History.
我十分想要那份工作
I desperately wanted that job.
但只有一个问题
There was just one problem --
我对历史知之甚少
I don't know much about history.
那你很了解生物吗
Do you know much biology?
别犯贱  米奇尔
Not now, Mitchell.
你的科学或者法语怎么样
What about your science book or the French you took?
你真走运我很爱你
You're lucky I love you.
我知道如果你也爱我
And I know that if you love me, too...
世界将会多么美好*
*What a wonderful world this would be
我真的摊上麻烦了
I really was in a jam, though.
我爸觉得树立冷酷疏远的权威形象
My dad thinks that he can motivate his workers
能激发员工的积极性
by being a cold, distant authority figure.
如果他的方法那么有效  回答我这个问题
Well, if his style is so effective, riddle me this --
为什么我从来不听他的
why didn't I listen to him?
大家好
Hey.
抱歉打扰了  我叫克莱尔
Hi. Sorry. I'm Claire.
今天是我第一天来上班  所以我来打个招呼
It's my first day, so I thought I'd say hi.
-你好  -太神奇了
- Oh. Hey. - Amazing.
你们居然真在冷水器旁边谈天说地
You guys are actually hanging out by the water cooler.
我得了口干症  长期口腔干燥
I have xerostomia. It's chronic dry mouth.
我  很抱歉
I'm -- I'm so sorry.
我只是随口说说  你知道的  就像...
I-I-I-I was just doin' a thang, you know, like...
话说回来
Anyway,
我办公室的大门一直为各位敞开
My door's always open... to everyone.
她是普里契特的女儿
That's Pritchett's daughter.
是的  但我不希望你们拘泥于我这个身份
Um, yeah, but I don't want you to think of me like that.
我是你们的朋友  是同事
I'm -- I'm a friend. I'm a colleague.
我就和你们一样
I'm just like you.
我是克莱尔  勤劳的工蜂
I'm Claire, you know -- worker bee, just...
见到你们真好
Great to meet you.
抱歉打扰了  回头见
Sorry to interrupt, and see you around.
我必须得表演一下
I do -- I got to do this one.
我是谁
Who am I?
你们可以在我身体里挂衣服
You can hang your clothes in me.
克里斯托弗-步入式衣柜
Christopher walk-in closet.
什么情况
What is this?
二位  对不起  这里停业了  我们在拍广告
Oh, sorry, folks. It's closed. We're shooting a commercial.
真烦人
So annoying.
我们只想喝杯咖啡
Listen, we just want to get a cup of coffee.
其实我们还缺少两位群众演员
Actually, we're short a couple of extras.
你们愿意帮忙吗
How would you two like to be in it?
-愿意  -听起来棒极了
- Yes! - That sounds amazing.
我看见了两位老人
Hey, um, I see a couple of old people.
这不是导尿管的广告吧
This isn't one of those catheter commercials, is it?
如果广告描述的太详细
'Cause if it gets too descriptive,
我会浑身难受的
I'm gonna squirm.
我刚刚就抖了一下
I just did it to myself.
我尽全力备好了
I did my best to cram for my lecture
美国独立战争这堂课  但是
on the revolutionary war, but, ugh.
所有的名字和日期都十分枯燥
All those names and dates -- it's all so dry.
怎样才能制造戏剧效果呢
Where's the drama?
戏剧部
早安
Good morrow!
天啊
Oh, boy.
你们穿的是什么奇怪的服饰
Oh, what is all this strange garb you adorn?
你们是从加拿大省来的捕兽者吗
Are you trappers from the Canadian provinces?
你们是来卖海狸的吗
Are you here to sell your beavers?
你是谁啊
Who are you?
价值64便士的问题
The 64-pence question.
模仿竞赛游戏节目
我在独立战争期间  曾穿过特拉华州
I crossed the Delaware during the Revolutionary War.
我在福治河谷度过了寒冬
I spent a brutal winter in Valley Forge.
我是谁
Who am I?
我完全不知道
I-I have no idea.
我发誓我不认识这人
I-I swear I don't know who this man is.
我当然是乔治・华盛顿啦
I'm George Washington, of course.
教学大纲上写着  我们应该学习
Our syllabus says we're supposed to cover
美国原著民在殖民主义开始前的状况
Native Americans on the eve of colonization.
是啊  美国原住民  印第安人
Yes. Native Americans. Indians!
威严和平的民族
A majestic, peaceful people,
他们依靠土地生存  看见垃圾时会哭泣
who lived off the land and cried when they saw litter.
课本上写的是部落之间常常发生战争
The textbook says many tribes were often at war,
朝秦暮楚  朝三...
with allegiances shifting all of the ti--
朝三暮四
Shifting all the time!
那印第安人和殖民者到底是不是朋友
So, were the Indians friends with the Colonists or not?
问得好  是的
Ah! Yes.
我认识一个印第安人
I know one Indian
他和建筑工人  骑车人
who was friends with a construction worker, biker,
以及交警都是好朋友
and traffic cop.
你们  没反应吗
Uh, do y-- nothing?
没搞错吧  居然没反应
Seriously, nothing?
你们的爹妈会喜欢刚刚那笑话的
Okay, your parents are gonna love that joke.
好了  普里契特  我来了  你有半小时时间
Okay, Pritchett, I'm here. You got a half-hour.
我的直升飞机在楼顶上等着
I have my helicopter standing by on the roof.
楼顶上能停直升飞机吗
Is it even built for that?
不能  所以你只有半小时
No. That's why you only have a half-hour.
我不确定时间够不够
Well, I'm not sure that's gonna be enough time.
我们要说好多事呢
We have a ton to cover.
我们得谈谈新的租赁合同
We need to talk about new lease agreements
以及工人的薪资福利问题
and the workers' comp package.
只剩29分钟了  我好像听到了嘎吱声
29 minutes. I think I hear creaking.
爹地  我好无聊
Daddy, I'm bored.
我也是
Me, too.
所以我不该在假期之间来工作
This is why I shouldn't come into work between vacations.
你去坐在娜塔莉的桌子旁
Why don't you sit at Natalie's desk
假装是我的助理好吗  亲爱的
and pretend to be my assistant, sweetie?
抱歉  我侄女马上就来接走她
Sorry about that. My niece is coming to pick her up.
莉莉今天在学校出了场事故  她...
Lily had an incident at school today where she --
普里契特
Hey, Pritchett,
你又不是我想勾引的单身辣妈
you're not some hot single mom i'm trying to seduce,
我没必要听你唠叨你家小孩
so I don't need to hear about your kid.
有道理  好吧  租赁合同
Fair enough. So, lease agreements.
迈阿密那处房产有些推迟
Okay, I'm getting some push-back on the Miami location.
普里契特先生  有位海莉小姐找你
Mr. Pritchett, I have a Haley here to see you.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
你好  亲爱的
Hi, sweetheart.
我在和我老板开会呢
I'm in the middle of a meeting with my boss,
万分感谢你来帮我
but thank you so much for helping me out.
没关系
No problem.
我上节课只给及格或不及格
My last class is a pass/fail.
那是社区大学  所以肯定会及格
And it's community college, so it's pass.
你好  我是查理・宾汉姆
Hi. Charlie Bingham.
瞧瞧你美丽的双眸
Look at your eyes.
我看不到
Oh. I-I can't.
我喜欢你
I like you.
你觉得我的裤子怎么样
What do you think of these pants?
是我们的新款之一
It's part of our new collection.
有好多拉链啊
It's, uh, a lot of zippers.
太多了  是吧
It's too many, right?
当我坐直升机时  拉链都戳进了我的大腿
And they poke into my thigh when I'm in my helicopter.
因为我有直升飞机  没什么大不了的
'Cause I have a helicopter. It's not a big deal.
总之  谢谢你
Okay, so, anyway, thank you.
你好像很了解时尚
You seem to know a lot about fashion.
关于几件衣服的款式  我想问问你的意见
I'd like to get your opinion on a few things.
-当然啦  -可以吗
- Sure. - Yeah?
-可以  -其实不行  她得留下来照看莉莉
- Yeah. - Actually, no, she -- she needs to stay and watch Lily.
你去照看吧
Yeah, you can do that.
你好啊  小公主
Hey, princess. Hey.
我超爱小孩子
I love kids.
爹地的办公室
Daddy's office.
你讲话才像小女孩呢
You sound like a little girl.
你想见我吗
Hey, you wanted to see me?
谢谢你"凑空"过来
Thanks for "Bzzzing" By.
我希望你"木有"在忙呢
I hope you weren't in the middle of a "Thang."
好吧  刚刚我确实有点失控
Okay, that did get a little away from me.
但说实话  我打破了坚冰
But to be fair, I broke the ice.
每个人都觉得你是个傻瓜
Everybody thinks you're a dummy.
不是每个人  不是的  实际上
Not everybody. No, as a matter of fact,
休息室有个人约我共进午餐呢
One of the guys in the break room asked me to lunch.
-他名叫陶德  -别说是陶德啊
- His name is Todd. - Don't say Todd.
不是吧
Oh, no.
你不能和陶德一起共进午餐
You cannot go to lunch with Todd.
为什么不行
Why not?
你不能和他有什么往来
You can't be associated with him.
直到一小时前
Up until an hour ago,
他的"办公室怪胎"身份都无人动摇
he was the office weirdo.
但他对我很好啊
But he was nice to me,
他还帮我装电脑呢
And he helped me set up my computer.
是啊  那就是他的工作  暂时是的
Yeah, that's his job. For now.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
我一找到新的IT人才就会炒了他
I'm firing him as soon as I can find an I.T. Guy
只要那个人能准时上班
who shows up on time
而且不会让办公室其他人觉得讨厌
and doesn't creep out the office.
我不能取消跟他的约定  他是唯一对我好的人
I can't cancel on the one person who was nice to me.
你可以取消   但你不会取消的
You can, but you won't,
因为你是那种会带饼干到办公室来的人
'cause you're the type of person who brings cookies to the office.
饼干哪儿去了
Where are they?
好了  没什么好说的了
Okay, we're done here.
好了  大伙儿  你们就装作随意交谈
Okay, folks, you're just having a normal conversation,
就像平常在咖啡店里那样  明白吗
a typical day in a coffee shop, all right?
明白
Roger that.
开始了哦  大家
Here we go, guys.
准备  开拍
And...action!
你最近怎么样  罗伊
How have you been, Roy?
心情有点低落
Ah, a little down.
海伦和我真的很想念孩子们
Helen and I really miss the kids,
但我们现在没钱去探望他们
But we just can't afford to visit them right now.
-你们考虑过反向抵押贷款吗  -那是什么
- Have you considered a reverse mortgage? - What's that?
-你的房子是有产权的对吧  -咖啡真好喝啊
- You have equity in your home, right? - This coffee is delicious!
后面的二位  我们听到你们的声音了
All right, you two in the back, we can hear you,
你们能像演哑剧一样用手势对话吗
So just mime your conversation.
哑剧  哑剧  我懂的
Mime -- mime -- I knew that.
我刚刚就是那样做的  跟着我做就行了
I was already doing that, so just follow my lead.
好的  抱歉  我们再来一次
Okay, sorry, sorry. We'll do it again.
但我们的其他表现都可以吗
But everything else is okay?
你们还没做其他什么事
You haven't done anything else.
-所以是说可以吗  -重新开始
- So, yeah? - Back to one, guys.
开拍
Action.
你最近怎么样  罗伊
How have you been, Roy?
心情有点低落
Ah, a little down.
海伦和我真的很想念孩子们
Helen and I really miss the kids,
但我们现在没钱去探望他们
But we just can't afford to visit them right now.
-你们考虑过反向抵押贷款吗  -那是什么
- Have you considered a reverse mortgage? - What's that?
你的房子是有产权的对吧
You have equity in your home, right?
-当然了  -他们在搞什么呢
- Sure, we do. - What are they doing?
她是在假装接电话吗
Is she answering an imaginary phone?
那简直好得令人难以置信啊
Oh, that sounds too good to be true.
你可以不用听我的
Don't take my word for it.
接下来亨利・维克纳会给你做更详细的介绍
Here's Henry Winkler to tell you more.
好了  停
Okay, cut.
后面的那一对
Couple in the back.
在  不  我懂了  再大点声吗
Yep. No, I know. I know. Bigger?
美国原著民和殖民者
The native Americans and the settlers
对土地所有权的观念完全不同
had two completely different ideas of land ownership.
最终  这些不同将引发战争
Eventually, these differences would lead to war.
快看  我都起鸡皮疙瘩了
Oh. Look, goose bumps.
好了  就到这儿吧  下课
Okay, yes. Uh, class dismissed.
我们做到了
We did it!
谢谢你半路拔刀相助  我保证
Thank you so much for stepping in. Oh, and I promise,
明天我一定课前做好充分准备
Tomorrow, I will do my best to be more prepared.
明天吗  哈利老师不是回来了吗
Tomorrow? Why won't Mrs. Hurley be back?
我也不想说出这么无礼的话
Well, I don't want to be indelicate,
但好消息是  我可能会成为你的专职老师
But the good news is, is I might be your permanent teacher.
-我不希望你成为我的专职老师  -怎么
- I don't want you to be my permanent teacher. - Oh, what?
你更希望一个大酒鬼来当你的老师吗
You'd rather have a raging alcoholic?
听好了
Listen to me.
我孜孜不倦地学习  才取得这么好的成绩
I've worked nonstop to build the perfect academic record,
我可不会让你给毁了
And I'm not going to let you screw it up now.
我160天后就要进行高阶考试了
I have an A.P. Test in 160 days,
我必须名列前茅
and I need to ace it.
你能助我登上顶峰吗
Can you get me there or not?
我可以像阿拉摩的勇士一般重振旗鼓
I can rally like the brave men of the Alamo.
你知道阿拉摩的勇士全死光了吧
You do realize that all the men of the alamo died?
他们全死了
They all died!
露希年长一些  所以她觉得自己就是老大
Ruthie's older, so she thinks she's the boss.
但对于一个小家伙来说  斯顿自有一套
But for a little guy, Stu holds his own.
他们有时候挺难伺候的
They can be a handful.
但是  他们总让我笑得肚子疼
But, god, they make me laugh so hard, you know?
我不知道你连乌龟的性别都可以区分开呢
I did not know you could even tell the gender of a turtle.
那当然了
Oh, yeah.
那叫"乌龟辨雌雄"大法  总共有8步
It's called "Sexing the turtle," And it's an eight-step process.
现在我们假装你的手就是一只乌龟
Now, let's pretend your hand is a turtle.
-好的  -你要把它翻过身来
- Okay. - What you do is you flip it over.
然后你要仔细瞧瞧它的...
And then you have to look right into --
好吧  我懂了  我懂了  我想明白了
Oh, okay. I get it. I get it. I think I get it.
我懂的  我的说教太无聊了  对吧
Oh. I know. I'm droning on, aren't I?
停下  求你快停下
Please, stop. Please stop!
你没有啦  你没有啦
You're not. You're not.
我就是的  不过我的家庭情况介绍得够多了
I am. But enough about my family.
跟我说说你的家庭吧
Tell me about yours.
好啊  我丈夫菲尔是个房地产中介
All right, well, my husband Phil's a realtor.
真巧啊  我刚好想买房呢
That's funny. I'm buying a house.
为什么  什么时候
Why? When?
实际上  我们今天就要进行最后的看房
Actually, we have the final walk-through today,
明天就签合同了
Sign the papers tomorrow.
那  那可是件大事  陶德
Th-that's a really big deal, Todd.
是啊  而且对我们也挺艰难的
Yeah, and it's a bit of a stretch for us, too,
但是  不行  现在时机正好
But, uh, no, the time is right.
我们  我们一定要买
We're just -- we're gonna do it.
"我们"指的是你和乌龟们吗
"We" is you and the turtles?
不  是我和我妻子
No, me and my wife.
妻...我很抱歉
A w-- I'm sorry.
你没说你有妻子啊  那太棒了
You didn't mention your wife. That's great.
我猜她的工作一定高端又高薪吧
I bet she's got a big, fancy, high-paying job, right?
她正在攻读硕士学位
Uh, she's getting her master's.
-哪方面的  -拉丁文
- In? - Latin.
陶德呀
Oh, Todd.
现在或许不是买房的最佳时机
This may not be the best time to buy a house.
我也不想做坏人  来跟你说这些
I hate to be the one to break this to you --
不不不   我来买单
Oh. No, no, no, no, I got this.
不  不用了
No, you don't.
大家预备
Stand by, everyone.
我真觉得我上一条拍得特别好
I really felt like I nailed that last one.
我还是觉得很不入戏
I still feel so stiff.
我都不知道该假装说什么才好
I don't know what to pretend saying.
你想得太多了  就从你的现实生活出发就好
You're thinking too much. Just draw from your own life.
比如  你今天过得怎么样
Like, how was your day today?
糟透了  我的亲儿子不想跟我拥抱
Lousy. My own son didn't want to hug me.
好吧  就用上这种情绪
Okay, so use that.
我的角色  叫斯蒂芬・威尔逊医生
My character, Dr. Stephen Wilson,
也很伤心  因为他儿子不肯听他的建议
Is also sad because his son wouldn't take his advice
而且他想在距学校一个街区远的地方就下车
And he wanted to be dropped off a block away from school.
他能理解他的女儿们这么做
He expected that from his daughters
他以为他的儿子会不一样呢
But thought his son would be different.
那太可悲了
That's so sad.
但斯蒂芬医生是不会让这件事
But Dr. Stephen wilson is not going to let that
毁了他和情人的早餐时光
ruin breakfast with his mistress.
其实  或许我们现在是时候
You know, maybe it's just time for us to --
放开他们的手了
to accept that we have to let them go.
或许是吧
Maybe it is.
好了  大家  开始了  摄像机要开拍了
Okay, everyone, here we go. We're rolling.
开始
And action!
你最近怎么样  罗伊
How have you been, Roy?
心情有点低落
Ah, a little down.
海伦和我真的很想念孩子们
Helen and I really miss the kids,
但我们现在没钱去探望他们
But we just can't afford to visit them right now.
-你们考虑过反向抵押贷款吗  -那是什么
- Have you considered a reverse mortgage? - What's that?
你的房子是有产权的对吧
Uh, you have equity in your home, right?
-当然  -请你别哭
- Sure, we do. - Please, no crying.
你哭我也想哭了
You're gonna make me cry, too.
本质上来说就是银行买下了你的房子
Well, essentially the bank buys your house.
但你依然可以住在里面
But you still get to live in it.
那简直好得令人难以置信啊
That sounds too good to be true.
你可以不用听我的
Don't take my word for it.
接下来亨利・维克纳会给你做更详细的介绍
Here's Henry Winkler to tell us more.
[《欢乐时光》中方奇的扮演者]
我可不想让方奇看到我这个样子
I don't want the Fonz to see me like this.
这件是样品  可以抵挡住
It's a prototype. It can withstand
地球上最极端的温度
the most extreme temperatures on the planet.
防水面料  可以去除汗水
It's waterproof, and it wicks sweat.
那也会令女人却步
It also repels women.
我知道  我讨厌这件  今晚我就烧掉
I know. I hate it. I'll burn it tonight!
事实上  这个烧不掉
Aah! Actually, it doesn't burn.
好啦  我们继续说租赁合同
Anyway, if we could get back to the lease agreements here.
你太厉害了  你觉得该怎么改
You're amazing. How would you fix it?
太宽松了
It's too boxy.
也许可以改成这样
Probably have to take it in here...
-没错  -还有这里
- Right. - ...and here.
我健身健得有些过了
Yeah, I probably overdo it in the gym.
该死的7%的身体脂肪
Stupid 7% body fat.
好吧  继续工作
Okay, so getting back to work.
我们在工作  为什么要工作
We are working. Why are we working?!
我得去卡波了  你想和我一起去吗
I got to go to Cabo. Hey, you want to come with me?
我从未去过卡波
Oh, I've, uh, never been to Cabo.
她不会去卡波  因为你老得能当她爹了
Yeah, she's not going to cabo 'cause she's half your age.
-你多大了  -谁在乎这个
- How old are you? - Who cares?
很快  我就会面如二十少年郎
Pretty soon, I'm gonna look 20.
我一直在密封蛋内冥想[类似太空舱]
I've been meditating in one of those pressurized eggs.
如果我去卡波
Well, if I went to cabo,
睡眠情况会是怎样的
what would the sleeping situation be?
没什么时间睡
Not much.
好了  够了  调戏到此为止
Okay, no, that is enough! No! No!
她是我的外甥女
She is my niece!
明白吗
Okay?
你这种可悲的中年危机
This pathetic midlife crisis of yours
危害到了公司
is -- is hurting the company,
我已经厌倦了给你擦屁股
and I'm getting so sick of cleaning up your messes.
你需要集中精神  你的行为要与年龄相符
Y-you need to focus and you need to start acting your age --
你真正的年龄  而不是"蛋内"年龄
Your -- your real age, not your egg age.
通常来说  有人跟我这样说话   我会炒掉他
Normally, if someone talked to me that way, I'd fire him.
但我尊重你的诚实  尊重你的激情
But I respect your honesty. I respect your passion.
和我一样  我也是一个很有激情的男人
It's like me. I'm a very passionate man.
集中精神做正事
Just focus.
你说得对  你说得对
You're right. You're right. You're right. You're right.
那个嘎吱声是怎么回事
What's that creaking?
预备  开球
Hut! Hike!
你跑错方向了
Oh, hey, you're going the wrong way!
方向错了  不是
That's the wrong way! No!
等等  对不起  你是对的
Wait. I'm sorry. You're right.
打扰下  布朗校长
Uh, excuse me, principal Brown.
妈呀  大多数代课老师就在课上放部电影算了
Yikes. You know, most subs just play a movie.
好啦  来点不同的  同学们
All right, do something different, guys.
听我说  我不能做历史老师
Uh, listen, I-I can't be your history teacher.
那些孩子学习非常努力  他们值得拥有
Those kids work so hard, and they deserve someone
真才实学  并且可以激励他们的老师  所以
who knows the material and can inspire them, so...
随你吧
If you say so.
我想问下
Hey, I was wondering,
你这是在训练什么战术
what kind of play was that you were running?
是侧攻吗
Was that supposed to be a slant?
高一的教练辞职了
Our freshman coach quit.
我这是变相在做保姆
I'm just a glorified babysitter.
接球手需要学习跑位
Well, your receiver needs to learn to run his routes,
否则四分卫不可能把球传给他
or the quarterback's never gonna be able to hit him.
-我在大学时打过校队  -好的
- I-I played in college. - Oh. Okay.
泰勒  你需要学习跑位
Hey, Tyler, you need to learn to run your routes.
什么位
What routes?
对  什么位
Yeah, what routes?
在这里就位
Well, you're gonna line up here.
跑三步
Take three steps.
一二三  到这里
One, two, three -- plant right,
左45度跑向球场
Open left 45 degrees up the field.
不如再来一次
Okay, why don't we try it again?
再来一次
Try it again! Tip!
投球时要用力  18号
Put some zip on the ball, 18!
预备  开球
Hut, hut, hike!
扔给他
Hit him!
有进步  做得好  再来一次
Better. Better. Good job. Circle back up.
总之  感谢你给我这个机会
All right, anyway, thank you for the opportunity.
你想接管这支球队吗
Hey, hey, how would you like to take over this team?
这个提议真有趣
Well, well, that's an interesting offer.
-工资多少  -没有
- How much does it pay? - Nothing.
你确定吗
Are you firm on that?
确定  但现在有体育老师的空缺
Yeah, but there's a gym-teacher position available.
-你做教练这活儿就归你了  -我可以穿短裤吗
- It's all yours if you coach. - Can I wear shorts?
可以  还有口哨给你
Yeah, and you get a whistle, too.
我穿短裤时总是有人对我吹口哨
Oh, I always get a whistle when I wear shorts.
我谦卑地接受您给的这份工作
I humbly accept your offer.
集合  同学们  来吧  快点
Huddle up, boys! Let's go! Hustle!
你知道快点是什么意思吗  10号
Do you know what hustle means, 10?!
没那么糟糕
It really wasn't bad.
等你了解他  就会知道陶德是个非常有趣的人
Todd is a very interesting guy when you get to know him.
他给你讲了他的乌龟吗  小露露和斯坦
Did he tell you about his turtles, little Lulu and Stan?
是露希和斯顿
Ruthie and Stu.
他取了这名字吗
That's the name he picks?
乌龟斯"炖"  白痴
"Turtle stew"? Idiot!
出了点小状况
Well, there was one little situation that came up,
但我觉得我处理得很好
but I think I handled it pretty well.
-他准备做一个大的...  -等等
- He's about to make, um, kind of a big -- Hold on.
玛格丽特  我为什么不能登录
Margaret, why can't I log in here?
我的电脑出什么问题了
What's wrong with my computer?
整个系统都挂了
The whole system's down.
看不到文档  也上不了网
No one can access files. We can't get online.
陶德在哪里
Where's Todd?
到处都找不到他  他的丰田车也没看到了
We can't find him anywhere, and his yaris is gone.
-我的文档呢  -搞什么鬼
- Where are my files?! - What the hell?
这事我可能知道一点原因
I-I might know a little something about this.
你做了什么
What did you do?
告诉陶德你打算炒掉他
Kind of told Todd that you were gonna fire him.
-什么  -我必须说
- What?! - I had to.
爸  他准备买房子
Dad, he's about to buy a house.
但他没什么意见
But he was fine with it.
他拥抱了我  谢了我
He hugged me and thanked me
告诉我这让他有时间早做安排
and told me that it gave him time to make a plan.
先生们  今天是全新的开始
Gentlemen, today is a new beginning.
新的开始可能很可怕
And that can be scary.
第一天还好吗  阔少
How did it go, Mr. Jet-setter?
很好  非常好
Good. Really good.
你想谈谈吗
Do you want to talk about it?
不想
No.
我对你们的要求  也许你们现在不太明白
I'm gonna ask things of you that may not make sense right now.
明天见  卢克
See you tomorrow, Luke.
除非我先见到你
Not if I see you first.
就是这样  笑容多灿烂
There it is! There's that smile.
但总有一天会懂的
But they will.
-老爸  -小家伙
- Hey, dad. - Hey, buddy.
-校园里不要勾肩搭背  -好的
- We're at school. - Yep.
没人可以保证必然胜利
Success is not guaranteed.
胜利不是唾手可得的
It is not handed to you.
要争取才会有胜利
Success is earned.
数据输入得怎么样
How's that data entry going?
很好  已经到1998年了
Good. I am up to 1998.
那时候我做这份工作差不多已经20年了
Ah, that's when I'd already been doing the job 20 years.
也许我应该听你的
So maybe I should listen to you?
那样你就可以提早回家了
Get you home a lot earlier.
谢谢你  老板
Thanks, boss.
今天  我们在开拓一条新的道路  同学们
Today, we are forging a new path, people!
唯一能让我们恐惧的  就是恐惧本身
The only thing we have to fear is fear itself!
[语出罗斯福总统  小卡扮的是华盛顿]
总统名言对应错位
Wrong president.
-给我推  -遵旨
- Just keep pushing! - Okay.